Records of the Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network
World Bank Group Archives
- Policy and guidelines development and supporting materials, 1994 - 2003 (predominant 1998 - 2003); WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-08; 6.05 linear feet of textual records
  - Policy Development Records - ESSD - Science and Technology - Correspondence - 1999 - 2001, 1999-03-22 - 2001-07-25; 01832177
  - World Bank Strategy for Science and Technology in Development - Draft Executive Summary - January 2002, 2002-01-31; 01832189
  - Policy Development Records - Social Development - Proposing an Articulated Social Strategy, Mission Statement, and Sustainable Livelihoods Framework - Correspondence - June 2001, 2001-06-05 - 2001-06-12; 01832192
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Promoting Environmental Sustainability in Development - OED Draft Evaluation and ESSD Comments - Correspondence File, 2000-05-01 - 2000-05-30; 01832216
  - Policy Development Records - Energy Sector Management Assistance Programme [ESMAP] - Correspondence - 1999, 1999-11-04 - 1999-11-09; 01832186
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Sustainable Land Resources Management [SLRM] Thematic Group - Formation - Correspondence File, 1999-09-01 - 1999-09-30; 01832221
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Fuel for Thought - Correspondence File, 1999-04-01 - 2000-09-30; 01832225
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - The Future of the Global Reporting Initiative - New York - December 8 - 9, 1999 - Correspondence File, 1999-12-08 - 1999-12-09; 01832217
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Global Public Policy - Correspondence File, 1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31; 01832235
  - Organization and Management Records - Safeguard Policies - Improving Development Effectiveness - Discussion at ESSD Council Lunch - Correspondence File - March 20, 2002, 2002-03-20; 01833541
  - Budget, Work Program, and Accounting Records - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Comments on OP / BP 13.05 on Supervision - General Correspondence, 1999-12-28 - 2000-01-27; 01833723
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Operations Evaluation Department [OED] Review of the Bank's Performance on the Environment - Reports - 2001, 2000-06-05 - 2001-03-06; 01833747
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Operations Evaluation Department [OED] Review of Environmental Issues in IDA 10-12 - Correspondence File - 2001, 1999-12-21 - 2001-02-01; 01833749
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Global Public Policy - Correspondence File, 1998-01-01 - 1998-12-31; 01832234
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Environmental Sustainability Issues in IDA 10-12 - Correspondence File - April 2001, 2001-04-06 - 2001-04-18; 01833750
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - OED Review of the World Bank Forest Strategy and its Implementation - Briefing by Uma Lele and Gregory Ingram - Correspondence File, 1999-11-23 - 2000-01-28; 01833752
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - OED Work Program Activities in ESSD - Correspondence File, 2000-01-10 - 2000-02-14; 01833751
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - CODE Subcommittee on Social Development Strategy - Background Documentation - March 19, 2002, 2002-01-01 - 2002-03-27; 01833753
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD and Operations Evaluation Department [OED] - Background Documentation - 1998 - 2001, 1999-12-13 - 2001-06-18; 01833754
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - CODE Subcommittee Meeting on Rural Strategy - Correspondence File - May 14, 2001, 1999-06-09 - 2001-05-14; 01833757
  - Organization and Management Records - Operations Policy Committee Meetings - Correspondence File, 1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31; 01833766
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Code and Board Meetings on Cultural Resources - Correspondence File - Janaury - June 2001, 2000-11-06 - 2001-03-01; 01833755
  - Organization and Management Records - Operations Policy Committee Meetings - Correspondence File, 2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31; 01833767
  - Organization and Management Records - Operations Policy Committee Meetings - Correspondence File, 2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31; 01833768
  - Organization and Management Records - Operations Policy Committee Meetings - Correspondence File, 2002-01-01 - 2002-12-31; 01833769
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Code and the Environment Strategy - Making Sustainable Commitments - May 23, 2003, 2001-05-22 - 2001-08-06; 30182412
  - Committee Records - Greening Committee - Correspondence File, 1999-10-15 - 2001-03-09; 01832602
  - Committee Records - GEF Trust Fund - Meeting on the Third Replenishment and Note on Structures, Processes and Procedures of the GEF - Reports, 2001-08-22 - 2001-10-12; 01832606
  - NGO - World Bank Committee - Meeting of December 6 - 9, 1999 - Background Notes for Ian Johnson, 1999-12-05 - 1999-12-06; 01832684
  - Policy Papers, Board Papers and Research Studies - Rural Sector Board Contribution to Operational Quality - QAG Pilot Assessment - Background Documentation, 2002-08-28; 01832859
  - Policy Papers,Board Papers and Research Studies - World Bank Strategy for Supporting Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development - Sector Strategy Papers as Building Blocks - Robert Watson and Rita Hilton, 2002-05-29; 01832806
  - World Bank / World Wildlife Fund Alliance - Briefing Paper for the Global Vision Research Project Steering Committee - January 15, 2000, 2000-01-18; 01833144
  - Community Driven Development [CDD], Rural Development and Water, Education for All, and HIV/AIDS Case Studies - Briefing Notes - Ian Johnson with Mamphele Ramphele - July 12, 2002, 2002-07-11 - 2002-07-12; 01833147
  - Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Briefing on First Quarterly Global Environment Facility [GEF] Secretariat - Bank Management Review - Briefing Notes - February 14, 2000, 2000-02-11 - 2000-02-14; 01833394
  - Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Bank - Global Environment Facility [GEF] Briefing - Briefing Notes - November 29, 1999, 1999-11-24 - 1999-11-29; 01833145
  - Organization and Management Records - Resettlement Committee Meeting - Inner Mongolia Highway Project - Background Documentation - March 22, 2002, 2002-03-22; 01833535
  - Organization and Management Records - SDV Joint Facilitation Committee Meeting - World Bank Civil Society Global Dialogue - Background Documentation - December 13 - 14, 2001, 2001-12-13 - 2001-12-14; 01833534
  - Policy Development Records - International Food Assessment - Correspondence - April 30, 2002, 2002-03-07 - 2002-04-30; 01831630
  - Policy Development Records - World Panel on Financing Water Infrastructure / World Bank Water Week - Report - March 2003, 2003-03-07; 01831703
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - SDV - Post Conflict Unit and Inter - Agency Standing Committee - Correspondence File, 1999-01-01 - 2001-12-31; 01831710
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Social Dimensions of Adjustment - Correspondence File - 2000 - 2001, 2000-01-01 - 2001-12-31; 01831711
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Safeguard Policy Framework - Correspondence File - 2000, 2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31; 01831712
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Operational Policy 4.12 Involuntary Resettlement - ESSD Correspondence File - October 1998, 1998-10-01 - 1998-10-31; 01831715
  - Policy Development Records - Environment Strategy - Making Sustainable Commitments - Correspondence - 1999 - 2001, 1999-10-08 - 2001-07-17; 01832187
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - World Bank Draft Energy Strategy - Correspondence File, 2000-04-01 - 2000-04-30; 01832215
- Briefing reports for World Bank President and related materials, 1999 - 2003; WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-04; 0.66 linear feet of textual records
  Series consists of briefing reports prepared by the ESSDVP and its sector departments for World Bank President James Wolfensohn. Records also include research materials used in the creation of the briefs (including reports, biographical information, and correspondence) as well as correspondence discussing brief requirements and meeting details. Briefs were created in preparation for the President's meetings with representatives from non-governmental organizations (NGOs), government agencies, and other external agencies and institutions. Topics include: climate change; environmental law; resettlement policy; environmental and social safeguard policy; agriculture science and technology; food security; climate change; biodiversity; energy; dams and water resources; forest policy; and empowerment, culture, and civic engagement.
  A small number of letters drafted by the ESSDVP for the President's signature are also included in this series.
  * See Records of the Environmentally and Socially Sustainable -- ESSDVP correspondence files ([WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-05](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/essdvp-correspondence-files)), of this fonds for a small amountof records that also relate to ESSDVP's interaction with the World Bank President. Records include briefing memoranda, correspondence, and letters written for his signature.
  - Briefing Books for Senior Officials - J. D. Wolfensohn Meeting with World Food Programme Executive Director James Morris - Briefing Notes - December 4, 2002 - ESSD Briefing, 2002-12-04; 01833221
  - Critical Ecosystems Partnership Fund and Forest Policy - Briefing Material for J.D. Wolfensohn for January 28, 2003 Meeting with Conservation International Chairman, Peter Seligmann, 2003-01-22 - 2003-01-27; 01833149
  - Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Jan Pronk - Netherlands Minister for Environment - Meetings - Briefing Notes - 2001 - 2002, 2001-04-17 - 2002-01-17; 01833148
  - United Nations Foundation - Background and Briefing Material for President Wolfensohn with Tim Wirth - December 3, 2001, 2001-10-17 - 2001-11-30; 01833139
  - Briefing Books for Senior Officials - United Nations [UN] Framework Convention on Climate Change - CO6 - Robert Watson - November 2000 - Briefing for J.D. Wolfensohn - January 2001, 2000-10-07 - 2001-01-21; 01833138
  - Role of Science and Technology in Food Security - Briefing for J. D. Wolfensohn - November 26, 2001, 2001-11-20 - 2001-11-26; 01833137
  - Spring Meetings 2001 - Briefings Prepared for J. D. Wolfensohn - April 2001, 2000-12-11 - 2001-04-23; 01833132
  - External Advisory Committee Meeting on Empowerment, Culture and Civic Engagement - Briefing Materias for J. D. Wolfensohn - July 24 - 25, 2001, 2001-07-23 - 2001-07-24; 01833395
  - Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund - Briefing Notes for President Wolfensohn Prepared by Ian Johnson - November 10, 1999, 1999-11-09 - 1999-11-16; 01833143
  - Briefing Books for Senior Officials - J. D. Wolfensohn Correspondence with Aracruz Celulose President Erling Lorentzen - March - November 2001 - Briefing Books - World Bank Forestry Policy, 2001-06-13 - 2001-11-29; 01833140
  - Draft Water Resources Sector Strategy - Letter to Water Commissioners of the World Commission on Dams by Ian Johnson on behalf of J.D. Wolfensohn - August 22, 2002, 2002-08-22; 01833146
- ESSDVP correspondence files, 1998 - 2001; WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-05; 7.04 linear feet of textual records
  Series consists of correspondence files created by the ESSDVP. All of the correspondence in this series was authored by, addressed to, or forwarded to ESSD Vice Presidents Ismail Serageldin and Ian Johnson. There are, however, different forms of correspondence. Numbered correspondence in the form of a Lotus Notes log book is the most voluminous; these records span March 1998 to July 1999 and include correspondence to and from both Serageldin and Johnson. Correspondence of similar type, but that was not managed under the log book system, is included from 1999 to 2001 and is exclusively authored by or addressed to Johnson. Included in these records are a small number of short briefing notes authored by Johnson and/or the ESSDVP for the World Bank President. Memoranda files created in 2000 to 2001 are also included in this series as are a small number of records filed separately that only contain correspondence between the ESSDVP and the World Bank President between 1999 and 2001. The latter contains correspondence related to event and meeting attendance and planning, information exchange, briefing reports, and letters written by the ESSDVP for the President's signature.
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4900 to 98-4950, 1998-07-29 - 1998-08-10; 01832386
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-5000 to 98-5047, 1998-08-24 - 1998-09-07; 01832388
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-98-00629 to I-98-00600, 1998-11-13 - 1999-02-09; 01832394
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-99-00100 to I-99-0150, 1999-01-19 - 1999-07-02; 01832395
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-99-00151 to I-99-00199 - Lotus Notes Log, 1999-01-15 - 1999-03-16; 01832396
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-5050 to 98-5078, 1998-09-07 - 1998-09-11; 01832389
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book I-98-00400 to I-98-00450, 1998-10-20 - 1998-10-30; 01832391
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-99-00200 to I-99-00250, 1999-02-13 - 1999-02-22; 01832397
  - ESDVP Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Ian Johnson - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-99-00300 to I-99-00350, 1998-10-07 - 1999-03-23; 01832399
  - ESDVP Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Ian Johnson - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I99-00451 to I-98-00499, 1998-11-19 - 1999-04-29; 01832400
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book I-98-00351 to I-98-00450, 1999-03-11 - 1999-04-05; 01832390
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book I-98-00500 to I-98-00550, 1998-11-30 - 1998-12-08; 01832392
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-98-00500 to I-98-00599, 1998-05-06 - 1999-04-20; 01832393
  - Chronological Correspondence Files - ESDVP Chronological - Correspondence Signed by JDW, Vice Presidents, and Directors - Correspondence, 2000-02-23 - 2001-03-23; 01832398
  - ESDVP Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Ian Johnson, 2000-01-07 - 2000-08-29; 01832401
  - ESDVP Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Ian Johnson - Correspondence with J.D. Wolfensohn, 2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31; 01832407
  - ESDVP - Vice President's Files - Chronological Correspondence File - 1999, 1999-10-20 - 2000-06-14; 01832267
  - Ian Johnson - Vice President's Files - Correspondence File - April - June 1999, 1999-05-30 - 1999-12-13; 01832268
  - ESDVP Chronological Records - Correspondence File - Ian Johnson, 1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31; 01832265
  - ESDVP - Vice President's Files - Chronological Correspondence File - Memos - 2000 - 2001, 2000-01-01 - 2001-12-31; 01832269
  - ESDVP Chronological Correspondence Records - Vice President's Files - Ian Johnson - Correspondence File, 2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31; 01832272
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Correspondence - Chronological Records - Ismail Serageldin - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4300 to 98-4350, 1998-03-23 - 1998-04-06; 01832280
  - ESDVP - Vice President's Files - Chronological Correspondence with JD Wolfensohn - 1999, 1999-08-24 - 1999-11-15; 01832270
  - ESDVP Vice Presidents Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4650 to 98-4699, 1998-05-15 - 1998-05-28; 01832282
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Correspondence - Chronological Records - Ismail Serageldin - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4500 to 98-4550, 1998-04-24 - 1998-05-04; 01832281
  - ESDVP Vice Presidents Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4700 to 98-4749, 1998-06-01 - 1998-06-12; 01832283
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4800 to 98-4850, 1998-06-30 - 1998-07-14; 01832384
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4851 to 98-4899, 1998-07-15 - 1998-07-29; 01832385
  - ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4951 to 98-4999, 1998-08-10 - 1998-08-20; 01832387
  - ESDVP Vice Presidents Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4750 to 98-4799, 1998-06-12 - 1998-07-02; 01832284